Hey guys, uh, I wanna talk about
how can you really build a project
for yourself in this course.
Okay? I'll demonstrate to you how I have built my course so
that you can also follow the same
and build yours to add to your portfolio
or to get the experience
to talk in the interview confidently.
The first thing you need is data set, right?
You can go to kaggle.com
and there are many, many data sets here.
Uh, just search the relevant dataset that you would like
to work on and download and start working.
Or you can also go to data dot go v, you have a lot
of dataset here as well, okay?
Or what you can do, you can go to publicity AI here.
You can ask a question. I am working on
a data engineering project.
I need really good data sets.
Suggest some portals
where I can download the data sets freely, okay?
And it'll show you some results.
And this is how I was able to find the, uh,
T-L-C-N-Y-C dataset as well.
And what I did is I went through this entire portal,
I understood what this dataset is all about,
and I looked at the data dictionaries,
which talk about the data, which is there in the file,
in the sense what are the different columns,
what do the stand for, what are the business attributes?
All of that is described in the data dictionary.
So if I click on this, it has information about the high
volume FHV trip data,
and it says each row represents a single trip, alright?
And what are the different fields you have in the dataset
and what each field represents?
We have all the information right here, in fact, okay?
So what I did next is I took this PDF
and I went to cloud ai, okay?
To cloud ai. And I uploaded the PDF over there.
I said, I downloaded this from the N-Y-C-T-L-C portal.
The dictionary is attached right here.
Imagine me as a data analyst at Lyft Company,
and I'm trying to optimize revenue and driver operations
because this data set could be used for optimizing revenue
and driver operations, right?
If you are to work at Lyft as a business team,
you would want to optimize revenue, right?
And driver operations as well.
So from the data set
and understood, it is a monthly data set, right?
If you go down here, it shows that
you get data for every month here.
So I told cloud AI that this is a monthly data set.
If the data source looks like this, okay?
Like what you have in the dictionary,
how should be my target data set looking like?
And I provide some more context to it.
Now, this context is something which I know
because I've learned a lot of stuff,
which I'm already teaching you in the diamond
membership course already.
Okay? So I said, data engineers will show data in par.
Key format about par key is already discussing their
purchase anyway, okay?
And I said they'll store it in a month partition format.
In aggregate layer, okay?
And I said, does it even make sense
to have monthly aggregations to help optimize revenue
and our operations?
I ask because the S3 data lake won't have asset properties.
Now acid properties, and I say, I will not be using iceberg.
Okay? So acid properties, iceberg, all
of this is discussed in the lakehouse course.
Anyway. So the point I made to make is here is
that I was able to add some more context here
because of me knowing about the Apache Park,
the big data related development,
and I also know about the Lakehouse functionalities.
I said the tables in target data lake will have hive like
tables, which analysts will access using Athena.
Okay? So I was able to kind of give it the context
and how would I, I come up with this whole thing
because I know about the different services in AWS
and the different concepts in data engineering, right?
So this is why you need to have the end-to-end overview
of not only services you have in AWS,
but also the different concepts in data engineering.
So once you have that, you can now go ahead
and build your own project, okay?
And then it gives some answers saying that, no,
you should go for daily aggregations.
You know, I went through that.
I, I had a, you know, a chat with that.
It suggested, you know, the aggregations, all of that, okay?
It even talked about hourly aggregations also.
And I said, I wanna keep it simple
because the, so somebody who's new
to build this itself might take about a week or two
or slightly more, okay?
So, and, and moreover for interview perspective, if you,
even if you go with just daily aggregations
at that point, it is good enough.
So I said I wanna keep it simple.
What will daily aggregations help me do? Okay?
So I was trying to, you know, understand from the analyst
perspective what they would be looking for.
So it, it kind of gave me some information here that, okay,
uh, we can go with, um,
identifying certain high value patterns,
like which zones generate most revenue.
You know, are Mondays more profitable than
Fridays in, you know, New York City?
So this helped me understand
how would the analyst think, like, okay,
and if you're asking the interview, uh,
if you have at information at this level, right?
Won't you feel confident before going to the interview?
You won't feel to have mugged up.
You will be ready to get cross questioned on any aspect
of your project and then it gimme a lot of information.
So I said, okay, fine. Now gimme a sample word doc
on this use case.
And then finally they able to generate it use case also I,
the document is right here, in fact, okay?
It was able to generate this
Entire business context, the source data,
the data cadence, all of that, the challenge, you know,
the key questions analysts, think solution, all of
that was given to me by the cloud ai.
So I went through that and I said,
the layer two silver will be cleansed data
and layer three will be gold.
Okay? So I able to see the AI is not always right, okay?
You have to be able to provide directions to it. Okay?
Now about the silver and gold, all
that is covered again, the lakehouse course.
Anyway, the diamond membership, okay?
Then it said, you're absolutely right, let me fix it. Okay?
Then it again updated the data in the document.
So I got the new one here.
Then what I said to AI is
that now imagine you are the data analyst
and you need to provide requirements
to data engineering team, okay?
To transform the road raw data into silver, then gold,
how would you provide the requirement
in a mapping Excel sheet?
Yes, mapping excel sheet is a standard way
to provide transformation, okay?
And let me create a comprehensive document for you.
So it took us some, it took some time.
And then, uh, look at this.
Now, this particular Excel sheet was given to me by
the cloud ai.
So this talks about the transformation from raw layer,
which is the silver to the gold, no, uh, the bronze, sorry,
the bronze layer to the silver.
So raw to curated and from curated to aggregated as well.
Okay? So all of that is, this was entirely given to me
by the clo, the entire,
all the mappings here, it has a function.
Now these are the fields that you have in source,
and you have target fields here.
So when you transform the D term raw two curated layer,
you gotta not just have the same number of fields,
but also create some more fields.
Right? Here, you see NA is shown here
because these fields are not in source,
but you are creating new,
when you are transforming from raw to curated.
And how do you do all of this?
Transformation is right here in the logic.
In fact, entire logic is given a direct pass
through your casting timestamp.
And you also have data quality rules here as well. Okay?
Likewise for curated to aggregated, that is also shown here,
in fact, okay?
And this talks about the aggregation fund function also.
In fact, you know, how do you aggregate all of that? Okay?
And then it says you go to join this data set
that you have here, you see this, this entire file
that you see with this fields.
Now this particular thing has, uh, two fields called
as pickup location ID and, uh, drop off location id.
So these are IDs, okay?
And you, if you wanna get the right information
that we already discussed in the s
membership courses, right?
You gotta join this zone lookup table,
the zone lookup table has the right information about
the actual drop off city, the boroughs, all of that.
Okay? So here it says you go to get the pickup,
borrow pickup zone, drop of borrow drop of zone by joining
with the file, the data file
and join Logic is also mentioned here, in fact how to join.
All that is mentioned here. This was
given entirely by ai, okay?
And you have the data quality rules also here.
In fact, not just that, it also
provided partitioning strategy.
How do you partition the data in a data lake
and the technical requirements as well, right?
The file format, how do you process,
where do you process a part spark on AWS
glue is a monthly job.
What is the query engine?
Everything is, you know, in mentioned here,
data retention, right?
For, for people with more experience,
you are think about governance as well.
So data, attention, the security, all of
that is mentioned here, in fact, okay?
And trust me, this didn't take a lot of time for me, okay?
To generate this, it hardly took about 30 minutes or so.
I just had to chat with the AI and updated document.
Of course not everything was perfect.
It was 95 to 98% perfect, I would say.
And because, you know, I had the information about the, uh,
big data part and then the, the lakehouse part, I was able
to guide it, to update it, okay?
So this is how you'll be doing it for your capstone project,
which will help you get the professional certificate in
applied data engineering.
And if you're really able to build this project end to end,
which might take for you about two, three weeks, okay?
Or maybe slightly more depending on
where you are in the journey, right?
How much you are finished, if you're finished Apache Park,
if you're finished lake house.
If you're not, you're gonna go
and, you know, learn those stuffs, okay?
And then come here and do this.
So building the capstone project will be your last thing,
but building this will give you the confidence
to not only crack interviews that will happen anyway,
but to also work in the industry.
I'm as assuming that you are
transitioning from a different background.
You see, we are used to mugging up
things from our childhood days.
You know, our Indian education system
is actually broken, right?
You know, when I grew up, I grew up in a Mara State syllabus
board, and I did not do a single project in my school.
I did not do a single project.
Even in, uh, my 11th and 12th.
I did that from, you know, Tica
and then even in my engineering, right?
There was only one project towards the end in the last
semester, eight semester, one project.
Of course now things may have changed,
but back in those days we, I, I had
to just work on one project.
So, you know, we are, we are hardwired to mug up things,
but that is not something which will actually help us in the
real world, right?
When I get into the real world,
it was a shock, a shocker for me, right?
I mean, I'm sure you're all working now
and if you're not working, uh,
you will know what I'm trying to say.
So if you truly wanna crack interviews, not just one,
but multiple interviews with confidence
and with every interview you wanna, you know,
Raise your offer that you receive from the companies,
then this is a must.
You cannot skip this part
because you see, when you're doing this, you'll be able
to utilize all of the things that you learned in AWS,
the big data purchase park, the lake house,
the data warehousing, all of that utilize,
and then form this project.
And what I've shared with you now in this video,
you won't find this being told to you like this easily
by anybody, anywhere.
And if you truly have this burning desire to succeed,
I wanted to commit right now by typing in the video below
that I will complete this capstone project no matter what.
I really wanna see if you're committed to really take action
and as the result, learn so well
that cracking interviews becomes a
byproduct of your learning process.
Now, for the Capstone project, if what I just asked you
to do is too overwhelming for you, I understand totally
because you may be having
no experience at all, too little experience.
And because I have people from different backgrounds in the
entire Taiwan membership.
So I'm gonna give you three options
right now for the caption project.
Three options. One is, what you can do is the
S membership project that you did, right?
You'll have to modify that.
You'll have to use airflow instead of step function.
You'll also have to finish A-C-I-C-D part of it.
So that's the first option, okay? For the caption project.
Second option. Now this depends on your how,
how badly you want things
to be done, how much time you have.
Second option is to go to the the N-Y-C-T-L-C portal, okay?
Now, in the cellular membership,
you worked on this project which used high volume FH
with trips data, right?
There are more data sets here.
You also have data sets for yellow trips,
green trips and fh.
We trips, pick any one of them, pick any one yellow trip,
green trip or FHV, pick any one of them
and enhance the similar membership project you did
by adding one of these as well.
Added the pipeline for one of these.
Well, in the same project, in fact, now you, you may want
to use the step function or airflow, it depends on you.
I'm totally fine. But you also have to finish the CICD part
of it because only then you'll be able
to have the confidence of, you know, saying
that I really worked on a real world project
because CSCD is used in almost every company now.
And the third option, I mean this is for people
who are really, really motivated, extremely motivated
and have some time and are not desperate,
but really patient enough to learn as much
as possible and and be really be confident
before going to for them.
I recommend going to Kaggle
or going to data dot, go OEV, wherever you wanna go, go
to complexity and ask for the data set
and then build an entire project from scratch, right?
You may want to use airflow or step function.
Anything is fine and I'll lay out the,
for all these three projects,
I'll be laying out some more guidelines in the next
video, okay?
You gotta meet those guidelines
because those guidelines will actually
help you use the best practices in data engineer projects.
I hope I was able to make it a little less overwhelming
than asking you to create a brand new product altogether.
Okay? Either of these three options are fine with me.
And if you do either of these
and submit the capstone project,
you get professional certificate in applied data
engineering, which you can proudly
upload on LinkedIn as well.
'cause you would've spent the time
and effort to gain that certificate.
It is not a ate of completion, it is a certificate
of achievement, in fact.
Alright, before you go to the next video,
I really wanna see your commitment type in the comment box
below that I am committed
to finish this capstone project no matter what.